# Konstantin Tenman

Senior Software Engineer Tallinn, Estonia

+372 511 1618 konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

### PROFILE

I have eight years of experience as a software developer, with a focus on Java. I commit to teamwork, building applications that undergo rigorous testing and seamless delivery. I love researching and staying updated with the latest technologies. I'm always searching for ways to improve my skills and make my work better.

## PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- **Programming Languages**: Java, Kotlin, TypeScript, Python Technologies: Spring Boot, Angular, Vue, Hibernate, JUnit, Mockito, WireMock, Kafka
- Tools: AWS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Docker Compose, Git, Maven, IntelliJ, Redis GitHub Actions, GitLab CI/CD, Amazon ECS, Docker Swarm
- Languages: English, Estonian, Russian

#### EXPERIENCE

• Bankera

Tallinn, Estonia

Senior Software Engineer

Jun 2022 - Present

As a key member of the Know Your Customer (KYC) team, I have led the development and maintenance of
microservices using Spring Boot and Java (versions 8 to 21), utilizing databases like Postgres and testing tools
such as Mockito, Wiremock, and AssertJ. My contributions have been instrumental in building robust, scalable,
and effective solutions for financial services regulatory compliance.

## • University of Tartu

Tartu, Estonia

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2022 - Present

• Teaching courses on Object-Oriented Programming in Java, Web Application Development, and Enterprise System Integration, contributing to the academic growth of students.

• Monese

Tallinn, Estonia

Technical Lead Engineer

Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

- Led the refactoring of a monolith into single-responsibility microservices within the Payments team.
   Spearheaded the architectural design of a strong customer authentication (SCA PSD2) solution and facilitated regular brainstorming sessions to foster team innovation and problem-solving.
- Played a pivotal role in interviewing and onboarding new team members, significantly contributing to team expansion and development.

• Monese

London, United Kingdom

Jul 2020 - Sep 2021

Technical Lead Engineer

• Systematically improved software performance and reduced operating costs, achieving a 50% reduction in monthly operating expenses for a critical application.

• Monese

London, United Kingdom

Software Engineer

Mar 2019 - Jun 2020

- Identified and resolved production issues, significantly increasing revenue. A particular solution for a single customer uncovered a substantial profit gap.
- As a member of the Pricing team, I delivered new annual pricing functionality on time and without significant issues, and led research on decomposing a monolithic application into single-responsibility microservices.
- In the Joint Accounts team, I was responsible for designing and developing the core logic of the Joint Accounts feature.

• Monese

Tallinn, Estonia

Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

Software Engineer

- Enhanced micro-service scalability by segregating database read and write operations.
- $\circ$  Successfully migrated 120M payments to a new queue-based Java micro-service, reducing the average response time from 60ms to 5ms.
- $\circ\,$  Introduced Angular 5 for internal tooling and improved seamless deployment on Amazon AWS.

• Designed and developed a micro-service for Recurring Payments with a test coverage of up to 80%.

• Codeborne Tallinn, Estonia

Software Developer

Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

- Developed responsive internet banking websites for major banking clients, including Bank "Saint-Petersburg" and the Czech online bank Expobank.cz.
- Enhanced team productivity and software quality by promoting best practices through code reviews, pair programming, and test-driven development.

• Knowit

Tallinn, Estonia

Software Developer

Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

Estonia

- Recognized as Employee of Q4, 2016 for outstanding contributions.
- Developed a full-stack, web-based application enabling users to create and search for services via Google Maps.

### EDUCATION

• Tartu University Estonia

Master of Engineering (MEng) in Computer Science; GPA: 4.67/5;

- Master's Thesis: "Developing a Web-Based Mini-Mental State Examination: Innovations in Accessibility and Efficiency for Cognitive Assessment."
- $\circ\,$  Recipient of Achievement and Specialisation stipends.

# • Tallinn University

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (BSc) in Computer Science; GPA: 4.73/5; cum laude

- o Bachelor's Thesis: "The Development of a Self-study Web Application Using Angular and Spring Boot."
- Recipient of Achievement and Specialisation stipends.